Hello everyone, how are you all? I am your
personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and you are
watching today's video. The host of this video is
Mr. Pramod. This Datta ji has
commented in the comment section on Exide Life's Jeevan Uday policy. If you also
want to know about the Jeevan Uday policy,
then check out the life insurance playlist on the channel.
You will find a video with examples,
which we can also see at the top of the screen.
Mr. Datta ji,
thank you very much for your comment.
Before starting the video, I want to remind you all that
every day, every video on the channel is based on your
questions and
according to you, so
like and share the video. Subscribe to the channel
and turn on all the notification bells.
Now, Datta ji, according to your comment,
I
would like to give an advice to all the people who want to pay a low premium.
Do not go for random policies. In such a situation, you should just
take a term insurance because this
insurance will be more suitable for you.
In endowment policy, you will also pay the premium but will
not get any returns and will
also get very little live news. Okay, so
now let's talk.  About Exide Life's Mysore
Income Plan, this plan is a non-
linked, non-participating life
insurance savings plan, meaning it is an
endowment plan that
offers guaranteed returns, and the company doesn't offer any bonuses.
You receive returns based on your payments. The plan has
three different options. You
can choose one of the three, and you wo
n't be able to change it after choosing one. The first
option is the Uniform Income Limit or
Income Benefit. The second is the Trust Income
Benefit and the third is the Increasing Income Benefit. The
benefits of all three are different. To avoid confusion,
we will
only discuss the Uniform Income Benefit in today's video
and learn about its
eligibility criteria. Let's first talk about the
policy term and premium payment term.
With a 10-year policy term, there's an
option for a 5-year premium payment term. If you opt for a 16-year policy term,
you'll get an 8-year premium payment term. Talking about the entry limit, it's from
10 years to 10 years.  You
can also take this plan for a 12-year-old child if
you wish. If you are 60 years old, you can also take this plan.
Talking about the minimum premium
limit and mode of premium, if you are
paying annual premium then it is
minimum ₹95000. If you are paying half-yearly then it is minimum
₹50000. If you are paying monthly premium then it is minimum ₹9000. If you have
taken a premium payment term of 5 years, then
if you are taking a premium payment term of 8 years,
it means your positive income will be 16 years.
You will have to pay ₹50000 half-yearly.
Rs. 30000 will become Rs.
7000 plus taxes. And the income benefit
starts after the completion of the premium payment term. The
income benefit period is equal to your premium payment.
Talking about the mode of income benefit,
you can take it annually, regular income
or monthly. 101% of your
annual basic premium. If you
want to take it monthly then your annual  It will be
8% of the basic premium. If your
premium payment is for five years, then if
you have taken premium payment for 8 years, then in
such a case your annual guaranteed
income benefit will be
125% of your annual premium. If you choose monthly mode for
income benefit, then it will be
10% of your annual premium. The
maturity benefit in the plan is Guaranteed
Terminal Benefit. See what is Guaranteed Terminal Benefit?
For this, a small calculation has to be done.
Guaranteed Terminal Benefit is equal to your base term sum. You will subtract from it whatever income you have received. Now the amount that remains will become your Guaranteed Maturity Benefit
or Terminal Benefit.
Understand death benefits, short on death. Now understand
what death is. It depends on the future.
If your age is less than 45 years, then
your annual premium means 10 times the basic
premium which is tax free
or
105% of the premium paid till the date of death or
minimum  Guaranteed sum assured on maturity,
whichever is higher among these three will be the term,
now comes the matter, what is the minimum guaranteed sum
assured maturity, I will
tell you this later along with Dharana, but
before that I want to tell you that if you are 45
years of age or more, then you will have the
option to
take 7 times or even 10 times your annual premium, now to
understand everything, we can take an example here, let us assume
that Mr. Di, whose
age is 30 years, has taken a policy term of 16 years,
he has taken a
premium payment term of 8 years here, so in such a case, his
income benefit premium period will
also be of 8 years because the income
benefit period is equal to the premium
payment, then the
rate of 125% will be applied
on the annual premium, now
according to this example, the rate
of premium that will come out will be
0.5
07% of your sum assured monthly, now if we are taking the basic sum assured here, then
we will calculate 7 lakhs here,
zero point seven  Zero percent
monthly premium will become 4949, if we multiply it by 12 then
annual premium of
Shriman Di will be calculated here, so as soon as the
premium payment is completed, after nine
years, the first installment will be received which is
125% of the premium, so here our annual basic
premium is
593800, if we calculate 125% of it then it will be 74235, now
what will we do to calculate the total, we will
multiply 74235 by eight, then 593880 total
income benefit is calculated here, when it comes to
maturity benefit, then we will get guaranteed terminal
benefit, so our short here is 7 lakhs,
total income benefit is ₹593880, if we
subtract it then 16120 guaranteed terminal
benefit on maturity will be given to them, now
we assume that Shriman Di's death happens
after completion of 6 years of the policy,
so in such a situation we will calculate the total premium
which is annual premium  If we
multiply 59388 by six then it will become 356328.
Why did we calculate this because we have to
calculate 105% of it, so it will become
374144 paise. If we multiply the annual premium by
10 then it will become
593880. You have to know the minimum
guaranteed amount because we will compare these three
and the total income benefit that we are getting here is
zero because if
we die before the completion of the premium payment, then there will be an
amount of Rs 7 lakh.
Leave that time, if death occurs, which will be
given to the nominee of Shriman Di and the policy will be
terminated. Now
before proceeding further, let us know about the surrender value.
If someone has this policy and has paid the
premium continuously for 2 years, then he
can surrender the policy. If he has
not paid the premium for two years and has stopped before that, then the
policy can lapse. Now let us assume that
Shriman Di is going to surrender the policy after completion of 10 years, then in
such a case the total income will be  The
benefit will be
₹148470 because 10 years have been completed and we are
doing it after that, and in this case, the
premium payment term will also be completed,
so the total analysis that will be done in the policy will be ₹
475104. Now, why will we need
surrender value factor, so
we have taken 16 years, here the policy term has been completed for 10 years,
so 65% here will be the
guaranteed surrender value factor which will be
applied on the total paid premium. Now,
since this is a guaranteed income plan, there is
no bonus, so after taking out
65% of the total paid premium of ₹475104,
we will subtract the income benefit of ₹1470, then we will
get the guaranteed surrender value of ₹146592.40 paise. In this policy, Mr. Di has a
reduced premium and gets the benefit of the policy as well.
The condition is exactly the same, you have
paid the premium for 2 years, after that you are not paying it, then there is a
grace period.  Later the
policy will be converted into a reduced pay policy
and for this we will need a
factor of factor which we call
RPU factor i.e. reduced pay
is factor reduced and what is a factor,
you will divide the number of years you have paid the premium by the
number of years you had to pay the premium
in the plan, now this will be the factor
which will be multiplied in the death benefit, guaranteed income benefit
and majority benefit, that is the
amount you will get, whatever
benefit you know you will multiply the factor in it, the
policy benefits will be calculated, if we
talk about loan, you can get up to 80% of the
centre value, the rate of interest is 9.5%
which keeps changing, the revival period is of
5 years from the time you stopped paying the premium till the
next 5 years, the
free look period is of 15 days on direct
buy, on direct buy
you get a free look period of 10 days,
thank you very much that you
watched the video diligently till the end, stay
with us because in the next part we will
know about its two different  So understand
one thing yourself and
explain it to others as well, about options with examples, that insurance is
protection and protection is never
taken incompletely
[Music]